# **Selena Flores**

Portland, OR, 97232, USA | 5205893209 netusersel@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

#### About me

I am driven to build accessible applications which, defined at requirements collection, aim to empower, charm, and include based on a thorough understanding of the customer - minimizing bias and maximizing value for all users. I love tackling challenging problems, creating engaging stories, and building strong relationships with coworkers and customers with effective, kind communication. Here's what I bring to the table:

- 3+ years of software development experience spread across classwork, personal projects, and internships
- 2+ years of project management and planning experience spread across DEI initiatives and SDLC
- 1+ years of customer service experience spread across food service and retail

#### **EDUCATION**

### **BA, Computer Science & Mathematics**

### 2019 – 2023 | Lewis & Clark College | Portland, OR

- **Coursework:** Algorithm Design & Analysis in Java, Graphics Programming in C, AI/ML in Python, Object Oriented Software Development, Partial Differential Equations, Linear Algebra, Real Analysis
- Achievements: JEDI Award, 2 offers of internship extension, Completion of an Independent Study

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### **Lead Backend Engineer Intern**

May 2023 - January 2024

### Lewis & Clark College | Portland, OR

Scheme, diagram, and improve modular frameworks and shared libraries. Administrate server deployment, maintenance, and configurations. Create and update readable documentation for a variety of technical skill levels.

- Quickly prototyped testing software for more accurate bug tracking
- Became backend engineering lead
- Enhanced performance, scalability, and useability of backend and game scripts

**Skills:** MYSQL, PHP, C#, Object Oriented Development, AWS, LAMP Development, AGILE, Trello, Git version control, Visual Studio Code, Unity, Terminal, Multi-Disciplinary team collaboration

# Chair of the Equity, Inclusion, & Justice Committee

August 2019 – May 2023

### Lewis & Clark College | Portland, OR

Manage DEI projects, a \$30,000 budget, and the hiring, training and orientation of new members. Develop, write, and implement strategic plans. Build strong working relationships with students, professors, and administrators.

- Committee Chair(August 2022 May 2023)
  - Created budget and wrote guidelines to initiate stipends for affinity group leaders
  - Provided a kind, inclusive safe space for committee discussions
  - Allocated budget, secured space, and wrote guidelines for the creation of a food pantry
- Vice Chair (August 2020-May 2021)
  - o Promoted transparency, accessibility, and publicity of grant program
  - Brought key insights to equity audit discussions
  - Lead communication for a growing subcommittee

# **Selena Flores**

#### Committee Member(September 2019 - May 2020, August 2021 - May 2022)

Became a consistent volunteer, voice, and advocate for marginalized communities
Skills: Discussion leading, Google Suite, Budgets, Equity Audit, Hiring, Training, Public Speaking, Scheduling, Tabling, Writing, Interpersonal Relations

### **Vision and Graphics Lab Summer REU Intern**

May 2022 - August 2022

# University of Southern California | Los Angeles, CA

Work closely with a PhD student on physically based rendering pipelines in Unity, attend research seminars, and present findings.

- Implemented a super resolution deep learning plugin in Unity
- Independently researched, schemed, and programed a ray marcher algorithm
- Presented at the USC Institute for Creative Technologies conference
- Actively participated in REU team building events

**Skills:** CUDA, C, Python, Literature Review, Unity, Graphics Shaders, Windows Command Line, Fourier Series, Neural Networks, Deep SDF, Public Speaking, Neural Radiance Fields(NeRF)

### **Teaching Assistant**

Spring 2020, Fall 2022, Spring 2023

### Lewis & Clark College | Portland, OR

Track inventory, assist students with coding assignments, and maintain student privacy according to FERPA guidelines.

Skills: IT Service Desk, HTML, CSS, Java, P5.js, Teaching

### **Projects**

Portfolio December 2024 - Present

Independently iterate UX, implement object oriented web code,

- Minimized repetitive scripting
- Created visually a striking user experience

Skills: HTML, CSS, JQuery, Javascript, JSON, Git Version Control, UX

#### **Hybrid Rendering Engine**

March 2024

Link three separate codebases and write novel render pass algorithms that implement ZBuffer, Ray Tracing, and Ray Marching algorithms.

- Wrote readable functions
- Created a binary tree data structure
- Implemented a recursive depth first search algorithm
- Intentionally managed memory usage

Skills: C, Rendering Engines, Low Level Programming, Algorithm Design, Git Version Control, X11

### **PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS**

Global Mentorship Initiative | May 2023 - Present

#### PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAINING

Full Stack Development | FreeCodeCamp | In progress